ワンダホー！
「おおさか」へ　いきまっせ！
そうだ　こんどの
「ワンワンわんだーらんど」は→
おおさかの　みなさん
まっとってな～！
たこやき！　あはっ！
たこやきが　たべたいな～！
（真方ジン）うっ…　あぁ…。→
カイト…　逃げろ…
愚者のパズルに関わるな。→
Kaito...
Run... Don't get involved with Fools' Puzzles.
逃げるんだ　カイト…。
Run, Kaito!
（レイツェル）ジン　大丈夫？　ジン！
Jin! Are you okay, Jin?
What...
俺は…？
「カイト」って言ってた。
You called out to "Kaito."
夢を見ていた。
カイトって誰？
I was dreaming.
Who's Kaito?
友達だよ。
とても大切な…。
A friend... of mine.
A really dear friend.
カイトが　大切な友達？
Kaito's your dear friend?
[無線]
What? It's so early.
（レイツェル）なあに？　朝早くから。
Good morning! Isn't the weather just lovely?
[無線]（エニグマ）おはよう。
すばらしい天気じゃないか。
[無線]（レイツェル）
フン。　早く用件を言ったら？
Will you get down to business already?
ディナーの招待だ。
メインディッシュは…　大門カイト。
I'd like to invite you for dinner. The main dish is Daimon Kaito.
Eating Delicious Stuff Solves Most Problems
Yahoo!
（井藤ノノハ）ヤッホー！
Yahoo and more yahoo!
ヤッホーったら　ヤッホー！
ほら！　カイトもジンさんも→
You do it too, Kaito, Jin!
せっかく　気晴らしに
ピクニック来たんだから→
We're having a picnic to cheer everyone up, so let's shout "yahoo" together!
一緒に大きい声　出してみよ？
「ヤッホー！」って。
（大門カイト）学園の裏山だけどな。
We're just behind the academy though.
あ…　アハッ　アハハハハ！
Don't be so stiff, Kaito!
カイトったら　そんな固い事
言わないでよ～。　ヤッホーって…。
Just say yah—
It hurts, dammit!
痛えな。
ん？　なんか…　焦げ臭えぞ。
Wait. Does something smell burnt?
Oh, no!
わっ！　いっけな～い！
Man, it's smoking!
ちょ…　煙　出ちゃってるよ！
ゴホッ　ゴホッ。
Nonoha's always so cheerful.
ノノハさんは　いつも元気だね。
無駄に　エネルギー余らしてるからなぁ。
She's just got too much energy left.
You've gotten along well ever since you were little.
カイト君も　幼なじみだけあって
仲がいい。
小さい頃の記憶がある
っていうのは羨ましいよ。
It must be nice to have memories from your childhood.
やっぱり　何も思い出せないか…。
Your memories aren't returning?
My bad. I don't mean to pressure you or anything.
あっ　いや　悪い。　無理強いする
つもりじゃないんだ。
分かってる。
僕も　思い出せたらいいと思う。
I know.
I want to remember too.
君や　ルーク君と一緒にいた頃の事。
The days I spent with you and Rook,
そして
レイツェルと共に暮らした時の事も…。
and my time with Raetsel as well.
だけど　僕が
失った記憶を取り戻したら→
But if I get my memories back, I might end up hurting one of you.
カイト君とレイツェルの　どちらかを
傷つけてしまうかもしれない。
誰も傷つけたくない。
誰にも傷ついてほしくない。
I don't want to hurt anyone. I don't want anyone to get hurt.
それでも　僕は→
So must I still regain my memories?
記憶を取り戻さなくては
いけないのだろうか…。
ジン。
Jin...
俺は　それでも
ジンに　全てを思い出してほしい。
I still want you to remember it all.
俺の知ってるジンは
いつも　パズルを前に笑ってた。
The Jin I knew was always laughing happily with a puzzle in his hands.
それは　俺にとっても
そして　ジンにとっても→
That time was really important for me, and I think for you as well.
大切な時間だったはずだ。
だから　俺はジンに→
I want you to remember those important days we spent together.
俺たちにとっての大切な時間の
記憶を　取り戻してほしいんだ。
ありがとう　カイト君。
Thanks, Kaito.
そう言ってくれるのは
本当に　うれしいよ。
It's nice of you to say so.
でも　レイツェルは…。
（レイツェル）私も同じよ。
But Raetsel...
I feel the same.
（ジン）あっ…。
レイツェル！
Raetsel?
ゴホッ　ゴホッ…　ん？
私も　ジンに
思い出してほしい。
I want you to remember as well.
私と過ごした　大切な時間を。
All that wonderful time we spent together.
そして…
パズルを　どんなに憎んでいたかを。
And also how much you hated puzzles.
それは違う！
You're wrong about that!
（レイツェル）かわいそうな　カイト。
でも　許してあげる。
Poor little Kaito.
Don't worry. I forgive you.
な…!?
だって
君は知らないだけなんだもの。
You just don't know
how much Jin had to suffer in Fools' Puzzles.
（レイツェル）ジンが　どれほど
愚者のパズルに苦しんでいたか→
君は知らない。→
You have no idea.
It all happened after you parted ways.
あれは　ジンが君と別れたあとの
出来事だから。
私しか知らない
本当のジンだから。
That's the real Jin only I know.
回想
あっ…。→
ジン！
Jin!
Why do such terrible puzzles exist?
どうして　こんな
残酷なパズルが存在する…。
どうしてだ　レイツェル…。
Why, Raetsel?! Why?!
どうしてなんだ!?
You don't have to say anything, Jin.
何も言わなくていいよ　ジン。
大丈夫…
もう大丈夫だから…。
It's all right. It's all right now.
ジン　思い出して
本当の　あなたを…。
Jin, remember your true self!
うっ　うぅ…
僕は…　分からないんだ　僕は…。
I... I don't...
やめろ！
Stop it!
ジンを苦しめるな！
Don't make him suffer!
苦しめているのは　カイト…　君よ。
You're the one who's making him suffer.
（レイツェル）今の君は　愚者のパズルだわ。
ジンを傷つけ　苦しめるだけのね。
You are a Fools' Puzzle now. You're just making him suffer.
ジン　大丈夫よ。
私がいるわ。
Don't worry, Jin. I'm here with you.
（逆之上ギャモン）ムカ着火ファイヤーだぜ！
ったくよぉ。→
Fuck fuckidy fuck fuck fuck.
カイトが　ジンの野郎と　ピクニックだと？
Kaito went on a picnic with that Jin guy? And they even dragged Nonoha with them?
ノノハまで巻き込みやがって
何かあったら　どうすんだ!?
What if something happened?
Something? You mean Raetsel and the Master Brains pulling something again?
（キュービック・Ｇ）「何か」って…
また　レイツェルやマスターブレインが→
仕掛けてくるって事？
But Raerae isn't such a bad girl.
（アナ・グラム）でも　レイレイって
そんなに悪い子じゃないかも。
You're so naive. Your Raerae's even got that president Enigma dancing in the palm of her hand.
甘い　甘い！
エニグマとかいう大統領まで→
好きなように操ってる　レイレイだぜ。
警戒するに越した事ねえだろ。
A bit of caution never hurts.
（キュービック）彼女の事は
僕も好きにはなれないな。
I can't really see the good in her either.
パズルを使って　カイトの心を
かき乱すなんて　気にくわないよ。
She used puzzles to trouble Kaito...
I just can't stand that.
アナが思うに
レイレイは　カイトに似てる。
I think... she's very similar Kaito.
（２人）えっ!?
おい　まさか→
Huh?
By similar, you mean she has an armlet or something?
あいつも腕輪をつけてるとか
言うんじゃねえだろうな？
I had Iwashimizu scan her, but there was nothing.
イワシミズ君で　サーチしたんだけど
つけてないね。
（イワシミズ君）ないね。
Nothing.
She's puzzling with her own power.
レイツェルは　自分だけの力で
パズルをやってるよ。
やってる。
Her own.
やっぱり　カイトに似てる。
She really is like Kaito.
とにかく！
エニグマもレイツェルも気にくわねえ！
Whatever! I just can't stand this Enigma and Raetsel!
Now the question is, how can I help Kaito?
さて　僕としては　カイトを
どのような形で　フォローするか…。
（イワシミズ君）不審者　接近。
不審者　接近。
ん？→
Intruder detected. Intruder detected.
危ないじゃないか！
Hey, that's dangerous!
That's my line, kiddo!
（テオレム）
それは　こちらの台詞だよ　ボク。
（キュービック）ロボット!?
A robot?
（テオレム）面白いものに
乗っているねえ　ボク。
You're riding something interesting, kiddo.
しかし　いかんせん
エクスタシーに欠ける。
But it severely lacks ecstasy.
イワシミズ君をバカにするな！
Don't make fun of Iwashimizu!
（イワシミズ君）イワシミズ君を
バカにするな！
あっ!?→
Don't make fun of me!
That's the crest of Amgine!
それは　アムギーネ共和国の…。
Oh, if you know that...
ほぉ　それを知っているとは…。→
ふむ。　賞金が懸かっている。
だが　所詮６５万ドル。
You do have a bounty on your head,
but it's only $650k.
大門カイトを倒す方が
より　エクスタシーを得られるのは→
It should be obvious even to babies that beating Daimon Kaito would grant more ecstasy.
赤ん坊でも分かる計算だ。
As if you could defeat Kaito!
（キュービック）
お前に　カイトが倒せるもんか！
I can't let that slip.
（テオレム）それは聞き捨てならないな。
I, the wizard of numbers, Dr. Theorem, am peerless!
数字の魔術師
この　ドクトル・テオレム様の前に→
敵など　いないのだよ。
数字の魔術師だって!?
The wizard of numbers?
フッ。　数字なら
カイトも　僕には勝てないよ。
When it comes to numbers, not even Kaito can beat me!
If you're so confident, try solving this!
大きな口をたたくなら
これを解いてみろ！
Solve this!
（イワシミズ君）みろ！
ハハハハハ！　これは美しい。
Now, isn't that beautiful?
だが　答えは…。
But the solution is 123-45-67+89-100.
簡単すぎるねえ。
Way too simple.
結構やるみたいだね。
You're not as bad as you appear.
でも　これくらいじゃ
数字の魔術師とは言えないな。→
But this much won't grant you the title of the wizard of numbers.
カイトの前に　僕と勝負だ！
Fight me before you go for Kaito!
面白い事を言うね　ボク。
まあ　いい。
You fascinate me, kiddo.
Very well.
腕ならしに　勝負してやろう。
I'll fight you as a warm-up.
Come to the puzzle stage I prepared.
私の用意した　パズルステージまで
来るがいい。
Don't make fun of me! Don't make fun of me!
（イワシミズ君）イワシミズ君をバカにするな。
イワシミズ君をバカにするな。
Is there a puzzle here?
（キュービック）こんな所に　パズル？
Now take this dazzling bunch of numbers,
（テオレム）さあ！　この　目くるめく
数字の羅列から→
最も美しい数値を
導き出してみろ。→
and find the most beautiful of them, kiddo!
It should be easy if you love numbers.
数字への愛があるなら
簡単に解けるはずだよ　ボク。
The most beautiful number? Okay!
（キュービック）最も美しい数値だって？
よ～し！
心の声
（キュービック）まずは　数字の
並び方の規則性を探るんだ。
I must first find some order among the numbers.
あ…　違う。　これも違う！
No. Not this either.
どうなっているんだ!?
No. What's going on here?
（テオレム）どうした？　ボク。
口ほどにもない。
What's wrong, kiddo?
You're all talk. I guess this is just too much for you.
やはり無理だったかねえ？
（キュービック）まだまだ！
Not just yet!
No. Not this. Not this either.
心の声
（キュービック）いや　これも…
これも違う!?
ああ　なんと美しい！
これぞ　数字のエクスタシー！
How beautiful! This is a true ecstasy of numbers!
A child like you would never understand though, kiddo.
ボクのような子供には
まだまだ分からんだろう→
この震えるような恍惚は！
This amazing trance!
What?
（イワシミズ君）何!?
（テオレム）言い忘れていた。→
I forgot to mention, but if you fail to solve this puzzle in time,
もし　制限時間内に
このパズルが解けなければ→
ボクの命は　エクスタシーの炎に
焼かれる。
then you will be ecstatically turned to ashes, kiddo.
そ…　そんな！
No way!
Our goal is to annihilate all puzzlers.
（テオレム）全てのパズラーを
せん滅するのが　我らの目的。→
ファイ・ブレインの子供たちは
その見せしめなのだ。
The children of the Phi Brain will serve as an example.
ハハハハハ！　エクスタシーとともに葬るのが
せめてもの情けだよ　ボク。
I am at least kind enough to bury you in ecstasy, kiddo!
I'll show you the Jin you don't know, Kaito.
（レイツェル）カイト。　君の知らないジンを
もう一つだけ　教えてあげる。
何!?
「パズルは鎖　パズルは鏡」。→
What?
Puzzles are chains. Puzzles are mirrors.
これは　あなたの言葉よ。
僕の？
You said this.
I did?
パズルは　鎖のように人を縛り→
Puzzles imprison people like chains
鏡のように
見たくない姿を映し出す。→
and show them their most detestable side, like mirrors.
だからジンは　パズルを憎んだのよね。
そうでしょ？
That's why you hated puzzles, right?
Right?
（ジン）
人を縛り　見たくない姿を…。
Imprison people... show them their most detestable side...
ええ。　思い出して　ジン。
Yes.
Remember, Jin!
私に　そう教えてくれた
あの時の事を。
Remember when you taught me that!
（鳴き声）
ん？　どうしたの　トリ友。
What's wrong, birdy?
（鳴き声）
え～！　キュー太郎が!?→
Cubie is?!
ギャモーン！
あぁ？
Gammon!
うそだ！
ジンが　そんな事　言うはずねえ！
You're lying!
Jin would never say such a thing!
ジンは…→
When I was starting to hate puzzles,
パズルを嫌いになりかけていた俺に
再び　パズルを教えてくれた。→
he helped me remember how wonderful they are.
パズルの楽しさを教えてくれたんだ！
He taught me how fun they are!
I trust the Jin I know.
だから　俺は
俺の知っているジンを信じる。
The Jin I remember didn't hate puzzles!
俺の記憶のジンは
パズルを憎んでなんかいねえ！
No! The Jin I know is the only real Jin!
いいえ　私の知っているジンだけが
本当のジン！
You only dreamed that Jin!
君のジンは
ただの　まやかしよ！
はい　そこまで。
あ…　ノノハ？
That's enough of that.
Nonoha?
せっかくの　ピクニックなんだから
そんな怖い顔してないで。
We're out here on a picnic, so don't make such a scary face.
バーベキューも　おいしそうに焼けたし
食べて　食べて。
The BBQ turned out quite good, so eat up!
This isn't the time for that!
お前　今　そんな場合じゃ…。
そうよ！　話の邪魔しないで。
Yeah, don't interrupt—
いいから　黙って食べるの。
Just shut up and eat!
人間　おなかがすいていると
ろくな事　考えないんだから。
People can't think straight on an empty stomach.
おなかいっぱい
おいしいもの食べれば→
Just eating delicious stuff solves most problems.
大体の事は解決するし。
はい　ジンさんも食べて。　ね？
Here, Jin, have some.
（レイツェル　カイト）あ～！
うっ！　ゴホッ　ゴホッ。
ジン　大丈夫か!?
Jin! Are you okay?
How can you bite into the onion?!
（レイツェル）タマネギなんか食べるから！
そうだよ！　タマネギ苦手なくせに。
Yeah! You can't stand onions!
Are you okay, Jin?
水飲めって　水！
フフッ　アハハハハハ。
Drink some water!
It's not funny, Nonoha!
笑い事じゃねえぞ　ノノハ！
だって　さっきまで　２人とも→
Oh, come on!
You were just fighting earlier about whose memories are right, but see?
どちらの記憶の中のジンさんが
正しいかなんて→
言い争ってたけど
同じ記憶もあるんじゃない。
You share some memories too!
私　ジンさんの事は
よく知らないし→
I don't know much about him, and I know his true self even less,
本当のジンさんも
分からないけど→
２人とも　ジンさんの事を
真剣に心配してる。
but you're both seriously worried about him.
その気持ちは　どちらも
本当なんだって感じるよ。
It seems to me that both of you are honest about that.
Isn't that enough?
それじゃ駄目なの？
ノノハ…。
Nonoha...
これ…　これって！
What? What's that?
あれか！
Is that it?
キュー太郎！
（ギャモン）なんてこった…。→
Cubie!
What the hell?!
あっ　あれは!?
Look!
It should be easy if you really love numbers.
（イワシミズ君）数字への愛があるなら
簡単に解けるはずだよ～。
キュービック！
あっ…　カイト。
Cubik!
Kaito?
何だ　この数字…　パズルか！
What's with these numbers?
It's a puzzle?
ジン。
Jin...
キュービック　一体どうしたってんだ!?
こういうの得意だろ。
Cubik, what's going on here?
You should be good at stuff like this!
I just don't know!
分からないんだ。　ありとあらゆる
可能性を検討したのに…。
I considered every possibility I could think of!
（テオレム）真打ちの　お出ましか。
Ah, the main character enters the stage.
As I am a gentleman, I shall allow you to solve this together.
私は寛大なのでね
２人で解く事を許可しよう。
更なる　エクスタシーを！
More ecstasy!
でかくなった!?
（テオレム）ホッホッホッホ　なんと美しい！→
It got bigger?
How beautiful!
どうだ　解けるかね？
それとも　無理かね？
Can you solve it? Is that an irraitonal expectation?
Irrational, huh? Of course, it's irrational!
無理だね！　無理に決まってる！
くっそ～！　さっきのと
数字の並びが　全然違うぞ。
Dammit!
The numbers are totally different now!
（テオレム）答えは同じだよ。
最も美しい数値だ。
The answer is the same! The most beautiful number!
心の声
（キュービック）パネルが大きくても
小さくても　答えは同じ？→
The answer is the same no matter the size of the field?
だけど　１８桁でも　３６桁でも
成立するって→
But if it works for both 18 and 36 digits... What number would fit that?
どういう数字なんだ？
あっ。　無限に続く数字…。
Infinitely long numbers...
もしかしたら
無理数なのかもしれない！
What if it's irrational?
無理数？
Irrational?
（キュービック）ここに小数点を
置いたとしたら　１．４１４２。→
If we put the decimal point here,
then it's 1.4141356237, which is the square root of 2!
「ひとよ　ひとよに　ひとみごろ」。
これは　[外:AF300B3D6122D539D0EE1E1E1600502E]。→
正方形の対角線上に
[外:AF300B3D6122D539D0EE1E1E1600502E]の無理数が隠れていたんだ！
The irrational number √2 was hidden in its diagonal!
さっきから　「無理だ　無理だ」って
言ってたのは　この事か。
So that's is why you kept saying "irrational"?
分かったぞ！　答えは…。
（テオレム）フン。　う～ん？
I've got you figured out! The answer is—
待て！
えっ？
Wait!
He also said, "The answer is the same! The most beautiful number!"
さっき　あいつは　こうも言ってた。
回想
（テオレム）答えは同じだよ。
最も美しい数値だ。
だとしたら…。
In that case...
あったぞ！
There it is! Pi!
円周率だ！
（キュービック）そうか。
最も美しい数値　それは…。
Ah, the most beautiful number!
ああ　そうだ。
Yeah!
この記号は…　φ。→
This symbol!
It's phi!
The number you want is the golden ratio!
求める数字は　黄金比だ。
つまり　答えは→
So the answer is 1.61803398874989484820458683436563811772030917980576—
１．６１８０３３９８８７４９８９４８４８２０４５８６８３４
３６５６３８１１７７２０３０９１７９８０５７６。
Ah, the golden ratio!
ああ　黄金比よ！
なんという　美しい　その響き！
What a beautiful sounding number!
俺に…　いや　俺たちに…。
There's no puzzle I—No.
カイト。
Kaito...
（２人）俺たちに…
解けないパズルは　ねえ！
There's no puzzle we can't solve!
（カイト　キュービック）うっ！
（イワシミズ君）撤収。　撤収。
Retreat. Retreat.
Ecstasy!
エクスタシー！
カイト！
Kaito!
（アナ）キュー太郎！
イワりんも平気？　けが　ない？
Cubie!
And you, Iwarin? Hurt anywhere?
（ギャモン）大丈夫か？
うん。→
Are you okay?
Yeah, but...
だけど…。
どうした？
What's wrong?
僕　カイトを守ろうと思って。
I went into it wanting to protect you.
でも　得意な
数字のパズルなのに→
But even though it was a number puzzle, which I'm good at, you still had to come save me.
逆に　カイトに
助けられちゃった。
そんな事ねえよ。　俺だけじゃ
あのパズルは解けなかった。
That's not true at all.
I couldn't solve that puzzle by myself.
Couldn't have won without you.
お前がいなかったら
勝てなかったぜ。
ありがとうな　キュービック。
そっか…　そうだよね。
Thanks, Cubik.
Ah! You're right.
やっぱり　カイトには
僕がいないとね！
おいおい。
You need me around!
Come on!
ジン!?
（レイツェル）来ないで！
Jin!
Stay away!
ジンを君に預けたのが
間違いだったわ。
I was wrong to let you take Jin!
ごめんなさい　ジン。
I'm sorry.
あなたは　私が守らなくちゃ
いけなかったのに…。
I must protect you.
ジン　大丈夫よ。　私がいるわ。→
Don't worry, Jin.
I'm here with you. My Jin. Only mine.
私のジン。　私だけの…。
う～ん。　さあ　いい焼け具合だ。
It's well-roasted.
カイトは
料理し損ねたみたいだけど？
I don't see Kaito on the skewer though.
Yet you seem quite cheerful. Did something good happen?
（エニグマ）そう言う割には　やけに
機嫌が良さそうじゃないか。→
何か　いい事でも　あったかい？
（レイツェル）
ネギは苦手って言ってるでしょ。
I told you I don't want any onions.
フッ。　好きな相手と
同じ事をしたいなんて→
You just want to copy the one you love.
So you can be cute.
かわいいところも　あるもんだ。
Hot!
熱っ！
ウフッ。
フン！　余計な事を言うから
罰が当たったのよ。
That's what you get for saying stuff you shouldn't.
アハハ。　いや…　そうかな。
I wonder.
やっぱり
俺の知らないジンがいるのか？
So is there really a you I don't know, Jin?
そうなのか？　ジン。
Preview